exactly like there's an adrenaline or
like a dopamine hit that you get when
you like reverse engineer something that
you never understood before and then it
leads to like a it freaking works you
know I love it
[Music]
[Applause]
hey guys our sponsor project Discovery
has dropped a new tool in collaboration
with Google's own Mandan team called TLD
finder okay picture the SubFinder but
for top level domains did I say anymore
check it
out Al righty guys today we have Matt
Brown with us Matt uh you live pretty
pretty close by two hours or so right
yeah just a little bit under two nice
man so he uh he made the drive down to
Richmond thanks for doing that and we
get to do a nice uh a nice live in
person version of the Pod um which I
always look forward to those are always
a good time um and man looking at this
doc I'm very excited um but I have to we
have to start at the very beginning a
very good place to start um and get a
little background about Matt Brown and
how you became the hardware hacking
specialist that you
are yeah so my uh experience with uh
cyber security and hacking started from
a young age I don't know I just loved
computers and playing around with them
at first and then I uh one day was at a
bookstore and I actually brought my book
from when I was 16 years old look at
this practical packet analysis uh so so
I bought the this book and it was all
about using wire shark and examining all
the packets that are flying across the
network dud check this out they're
analyzing HTTP in wire shark you know
like oh my gosh this is great I love
this there was a lot of clear text HTTP
flying around back then um and so I got
that book and I was hooked and so I was
just running wire shark and watching
what kind of traffic my computer was
generating and super interested in
understanding like every packet how it
works how TCP UDP works all that stuff
and so uh that's kind of got me hooked I
also tried a little wi-fi hacking at
home on my on my parents a weap uh Wii
back in the day that was still a thing
so uh yeah I mean obviously super easy
but you felt like this like hacker God
when you could like run a program and
have it print out the Wi-Fi password in
a black terminal right go unbelievable
man I I remember the first time I I
cracked a web Network also my home
network at the time yeah man it it what
a rush yeah so so so following that I
went to college I started as computer
science later transferred to Mis because
I didn't want to take physics one and
two or Cal 3 dude that those are so hard
man so but you did CS I would have
assumed that you did like Computer
Engineering yeah so I eventually came
full circle to that in grad in in grad
school but in my undergrad just uh got
in interested in general hacking and
security we had an awesome uh
information security student group at
Iowa State and they were talking my
freshman year about uh all all of these
session tokens that would be flying
around in clear text and I was also in
my first programming class at the time
and it was a Java programming class so
back in this would have been 2010 back
then Facebook thought it was a good idea
they had https on the login page but
nowhere else on the website oh my gosh
so and and and later later on no joke
Facebook made it an optional feature you
could drill down into the settings of
your Facebook account and optionally opt
into https every
no in the actual settings for the in the
settings for your account you could opt
into this technology called wow dude so
at that point there was session tokens
and stuff like that flying around and
playing text for Facebook they were
flying around and on college campus at
the time uh encrypted Wi-Fi was not as
popular so oh my gosh you hop on and man
open wi-fi open wi-fi so literally
flying through the air were session
tokens and so I I might have grabbed a
couple of those
from my friends Facebook Browser you
know sessions and pop their Facebook
accounts uh pretty sure it's uh more
than seven years ago stat limitations
yeah it's all gone so wow dude that's
crazy man yeah it was the Wild Wild West
and I remember um one of the first
things I did in college was we had like
a computer science 101 course and they
were supposed to like have you you know
you're supposed to build something it
was a very like abstract assignment
they're like build something and like
present it for everybody and we're like
okay sure and so what we did was we
built a um a a system where we would get
FTP credentials as they were coming over
the wire and we demoed this whole like
hack and you know this person would log
with FTP and then the hacker would like
grab it and and that sort of thing and
um with man in the middle and our our
our professor walks up to us afterwards
and he's like that was great you guys
don't have to come to class for the rest
of the semester if you want and I'm like
oh my gosh I love you so he was like a
TA you know he's like a like a grad
student like a student that was teaching
this course um so yeah lots of good
times with that but the days and I
actually thought that the days of you
know seeing that sort of stuff being
able to to proxy and men in the middle
and get all those tokens were gone but
actually we've got some some exciting
stuff on the on the dock today about
that so we'll swing back around to that
um so you're in college you're stealing
you know Facebook your text credentials
and that sort of thing freshman year
sophomore year they started to actually
crack down on that but um yeah yeah and
and the other really cool thing we had
at College were these cyber defense
competitions where uh you'd give be
given about a month to prepare they give
you a bunch of VMS you with a bunch of
holes in them you know purpose purposely
put there web apps vulnerable to all
sorts of stuff and you had to go and
secure those and then they brought in
real world pent testers professional
pent testers to come and like test you
for eight hours on a Saturday what was
it what was those called those
competitions uh cuz I competed in it as
well there there's there's a few
different levels of them yeah so Iowa
state does their own at my the college I
was at um but there are a like National
Collegiate cyber defense competition
can't remember the name of it but it was
so it was so much fun man because uh the
one we did you could you could be on the
offensive or you could be on the
defensive so you've got to balance your
time between hacking other people's
stuff and securing your own stuff oh
that's awesome and it was it was pretty
cool it was really fun that was cool so
yeah my experience at Iowa State is uh
as an undergrad was on the defensive
side you couldn't go hang out with the
but in grad school they let some of the
grad students go and hang with the
professional pentesters and be on the
red team and that's where a lot of my
offensive skills came from and my start
to uh yeah professional pentesting wow
it's cool because you get to work right
alongside you know propen testers that's
that's a really cool opportunity I'm
glad to hear College was good for you
with that I really for for me like my
college experience was very much like
trying to claw some some semblance of
cyber security into my curriculum
because the only piece of curriculum we
had at the time for cyber security was
this one course where it was all like
theoretical cyber security they're like
you know here's what this is but no hens
on nothing and so I went to the the
professor and I was like please like let
me do some Labs every couple weeks and
she's like sure no problem like and and
so we we were able to do that and we got
the cyber security club up and running
and then we were able to get some good
labs in place but um it's good to hear
that some universities
especially earlier on too um were were
doing that at a at a good level and
getting students into this sort of thing
yeah no that was a big thing uh Doug
Doug Jacobson he's the head of the
information security department at Iowa
State he was kind of been on the
Forefront of that you know focusing on
Ed practical education for for engineers
not theoretical you know stuff that
actually hands on you know at the end of
the day you know college it's kind of
hard for the colleges to keep up with
the pace of it you know but end of the
day if you actually have your hands on
something and you're actually doing
something you're going to get some
semblance of experience right is you
know rather than theoretical stuff so I
would definitely rather have older
material that is you know might be a
little bit out of date but is Hands-On
than Cutting Edge stuff and not Hands-On
education um I agree so not a whole fan
of the whole college process anyway but
whatever okay so so fast forward I mean
do you jump right into red team stuff as
you come out of college or how does that
go yeah so uh So speaking speaking of
all those competitions I uh also won a
like forensics competition that like
locky Martin put on and and that brought
me to a job opportunity that was out in
the northern Virginia area here so
that's what brought my family out here
um it wasn't exactly the best job for me
so I hopped around to some startups and
uh and and then I got a job opportunity
to actually move back into iot hacking
which had always been a side passion
project of mine but now I got to do it
professionally which was a pretty big
blessing that's awesome man okay and
then fast forward a little bit we are
this is our paths have not crossed to
this point yeah and then I go to this uh
live hacking event in 2023 and you know
I Joel and I are hacking on a on an iot
device um we're crushing it we've got
shells we're so pleased and then we show
up to this event and in freaking there's
like rumors going around like mat mat
Matt Brown he's shells you know random
induction sh shells for days you know
and and we're like what's going on and
and you had so many bugs at that event
man you guys absolutely crushed it um so
that was my first introduction to you
there and you guys you guys walked away
with the NBA that time we did uh my
first experience this is probably not
the normal uh bug Bounty path but my
first ever submitted bugs were at the
live hacking event that I got the NBA
chat so that was an interesting
introduction to bug Bounty for sure you
got plus one into that event I did yeah
so uh yeah random deduction uh Jesse she
invited me on uh found me through my
YouTube channel so I know we've been
talking a bunch about content creation
so uh yeah she found me through a
YouTube video where I was uh doing some
firmware extraction on an Amazon Echo
device um and that yeah so that happened
to be related to uh the target of this
event and so uh yeah and and this this
event was made for a hardware hacker
right because I think it was hacker
one's first Hardware only or or that was
the majority of the the scope for this
event so uh definitely an event that was
made for me dude that was s that was
very much so one of my favorite events
that I've ever been to just because it's
a different skill set for me and I got
to also see Joel really shine in his
area you know that he he really loves so
um yeah what a what a great memory that
one and we definitely want to have
random deduction Jesse on as well I I've
talked to her a couple times about
coming on the Pod so we got to get that
on the books because she's also got a
tremendous amount of knowledge in in a
variety of areas not even just you know
iot and Hardware hacking stuff but
outside of that as well um so
I guess clearly you had some experience
with network pen testing from the
competitions you um you know did some
practical packet analysis so we got some
binary level stuff you know protocols
that sort of thing
um what other pieces did you kind of
pull together because iot hacking is
such a challenging specialization
because of the fact that it's so broad
you know you you have to have some
reverse engineering you have to have
some you know networking experience
you've got to have web stuff you've got
to be able to do source code review like
all and then Hardware you know obviously
Hardware right um and so like where
where did you get the web hacking skills
and the the other components that you
need to be able to do the stuff you do
today yeah that's a good question I
think what makes me good at all this
Hardware stuff and like you said or or
hacking an iot system because it's not
just a hardware device right there's you
know there maybe there's a mobile app
that controls it or and then there's
talking to web apis there's there's all
these different components and I just
feel like over my time in technology
I've fought tooth and nail to to try to
be as much of a generalist as I can and
to understand a whole breadth of
Technologies and not be like I'm the
hardware only Kai because there are some
Hardware security only people out there
who are like finding bugs in like Intel
or AMD chips right that's not how deep I
go into the hardware side of things I
like to understand the iot system as a
system where there is a embedded device
you know with code to reverse engineer
that has Network Services that's
communicating over the network so you
have data in transit and in and and
stored right and so it's a cool way for
me to get to keep learning about all
these different Technologies because I
just love learning about technology I
think that's what got me interested in
this uh in computers at a young age
because there was kind of this Limitless
exploration you could do into the
digital world all components yeah yeah
no that and that's that's one of the
things you know that we've we've got
here as well on the schedule to talk
about is like iot hacking as a
specialization I think is
underrepresented in the bug Bounty
Community I think it's really hard to
find good Hardware hackers that will go
and hack on these programs yeah um and I
think one of the number one problems
with it is and why it's not there aren't
more people going down that path is is
really hard because you are constantly
learning and you are const L you know
having to use all of this information
from all the various um different
disciplines of hacking um to attack the
holistic system that is an iot device
because there's going to be a user
interface you know there's going to be
backend services that are listening
there's going to be you know local
privilege escalations right you know
that sort of thing so there's it's so
expansive um but yeah I guess I guess
that makes sense that it's really well
fitted towards somebody who wants to be
a generalist or someone that wants to be
a lifelong learner and always come up
against stuff that they don't fully
understand yeah no no the some of the
funnest uh bugs to find are when I have
to develop a new skill in order to
attack problem how reing is that to yeah
exactly like there's an adrenaline or
like a dopamine hit that you get when
you like reverse engineer something that
you never understood before and then it
leads to like a freaking works exactly I
love it yeah I talked about this bug in
in my Defcon talk um and it was the
first time that I'd ever like written a
python script from the spec to exploit a
binary protocol oh yeah and I was like
and I was like man it just feels like
I'm G to get some like something wrong
here and of course like I I had to tweak
in a couple places but eventually like
within like an hour it was working and I
was like whoa this is like I this is not
magic like they actually just built it
like the spec um yeah man so so
rewarding um so yeah I'm looking at this
list of of you know cross cross field
knowledge that we that I had here and
and there's there's so many I mean like
we were talking about earlier today
without giving too much information away
but there's a mobile hacking component
too to a lot of these iot devices
because they'll be running off of like
um you know some bastardized version of
Android right and they've got like all
these like super weird apks that have no
UI and or just like a service running in
the background you know all sorts of
things on there um so there's a
component to that too and then there's
the hardware hacking piece the web
hacking all of those so lots of lots of
really cool pieces that come into the
whole iot system yeah I would say to to
that point and to somebody who is
intimidated by uh you know hacking on an
iot Target because of that like you can
bring your one expertise in one of those
areas to bear on the Target and I think
I think I get get into this in the doc
but um the hardware hacking skills all
this super technical advanced stuff you
it gives you more uh more attack surface
to look at right so you had Jason hadock
on and like to talk about the whole
Recon thing and how it just gives you
more stuff to hack on D I love that you
listen and can quote every episode of
this podcast he's quoted like four or
five episodes today just in our like two
hours of conversation so I I'm caught up
I think we I'm caught up on all the epod
so um in there there there's there's an
interesting analogy it's not going to be
perfect but in the hardware world right
the more you dig into the hardware so
like I don't dig into the hardware for
the Hardware's sake I dig into it to
find bugs oftentimes in the so in the
actual software running on the device or
in a mobile application that or or a
mobile API that is in this whole iot
system right and like I think of it like
it's Recon right it is Recon for for
these iot devices for you to be able to
understand what you're actually working
on you know because at the end of the
day the most impct is going to be some
remote vulnerability right that can
allow you to pone the the iot device
right and and if it's a remote
vulnerability it's coming from some you
know service that's sitting on that on
that device that you can interact with
and for that you need to get your hands
on what that software is yeah and that's
the goal of a lot of the hardware
hacking piece right is to be able to get
at that uh you know internal firmware
and understand what's happening there a
little bit better absolutely yeah so
like every iot uh hacking exercise
starts out as a blackbox assessment you
have this device sitting in front of you
you know nothing about it you could
maybe like interact with some of the
Network Services over the network but
you don't really know what's going on
inside the the hardware hacking the
firmware extraction the getting a uart
shell on the device those are all tools
that's going to turn that black box
assessment a little bit more into a gray
or a white box assessment and and get
you access to more stuff to hack on
absolutely okay so so just talking about
I iot hacking as a specialization again
you know the first problem that I men I
I wanted to bring a couple of these
problems to you that I think present
themselves to hackers trying to get into
iot hacking as a specialization the
first one of course was the breath of
knowledge that you needed um but the
other one that I had here was how much
upstart time there is to find a
vulnerability right so me as a web guy
and I struggle with this all the time
because of the concept of opportunity
cost right like do I just log into a web
application and start turning attack
vectors right on that web application
and start turning out bugs or do I spend
for me what often turns to be you know
16 24 hours of of work hours like
working specifically on uh extracting
the firmware getting my hands on like
something so where I can actually start
even testing these Hardware devices
right um so I guess how how do you
address that and how do you weigh the I
mean obviously there's a lot of passion
for iot devices with you but how do you
weigh the pros and cons of that and do
you have any advice to hackers that are
just coming up and starting to come into
iot hacking on
that the the cost of even getting
started yeah so I guess the one thing is
when you look at Bounty tables a good
program is going to have much more uh
much higher Bounty tables for the device
category than you know it's usually
device mobile uh web is is what you kind
of see a tier system um so there is more
of an investment and and there's there
is a risk to your time right you're
talking about that opportunity cost
there there absolutely is
but oftentimes what I think you find at
the at the end of that exercise is a lot
of untouched scope because of that
barrier to entry that's big so I I like
like an analogy in the in the mobile
space is you know mobile apis are not as
tested as much as your your web apis
because there's this barrier to entry of
unpinning the app right in an in an even
greater sense there's this bar there's a
bigger barrier to entry in the hardware
world but there apis that are that that
that device interacts with or services
that run on the device that no one has
ever really assessed because maybe they
had a pentest one time and the pentester
like clicked scan against the IP of this
system and like no no real assessment
with any reverse engineering or
understanding of what's going on on so
wow sometimes these these devices that
make their way into bug boundy programs
they could actually be completely
unassessed they could they could yeah
yeah that's crazy man yeah no that makes
sense there's definitely a good amount
of reward there and I I like what you
said about having higher Hardware um
Bounty tables I think that's really good
I think also and this is something we'll
cover a little bit later on as well but
I think people coming from the web or
mobile world you know even talented
hackers in those spaces have a hard time
with attack Vector ideation for Hardware
devices like what actually constitutes a
vulnerability you know in a hardware
device so I think that's that's another
challenging piece of it so if you can
nail that down you can start thinking
okay well
maybe I could get that you know 88k
medium you know that there is in the
device World versus like a thousand
right in the web World um and so that
yeah I think that that I think you've
said it on the podcast as like a
full-time bug Bounty you're like I'll
report a low or a medium right I'll do
that all day long like especially when
those Bounty tables are advantageous for
me like a handful of mediums I'm I'm all
in for this yeah you're you're all set I
mean you're you're out earning some
crits on on uh on web scope often times
yeah and especially when you think about
the CVSs uh I think I mentioned this in
the doc right like as harder hackers a
lot of times yes of course we'd love our
attack to be remote you know over the
network but a lot of times we're sitting
uh in that adjacent category and so uh
it's sometimes hard to get the high or
the crit you need especially when those
other categories I haven't had a bunch
of experience with CVSs scoring Hardware
vulnerabilities I mean how does it do it
is not as built out for the
Hardware scope it it just isn't and the
result of that good programs what a good
bug Bounty program will do is they'll
say yeah yeah we understand there's this
CVSs thing but we understand the threat
model of our device better and things
that might have technically been you
know a high got called a crit or medium
get called a high because they
understand the the context that that
device lives in um I haven't had too
many programs be super strict about CVSs
they usually have their own internal uh
rating system so I'm
wondering how doing something like
providing a initial research stipend for
Hardware hackers would really I think I
think for me that would be an extremely
motivating thing right so if like a like
a program comes on and says like hey um
you know we're we're gonna be offering
$1,000 you know $2,000 to anybody who
accepts the hardware devices and says
we're going to give shot right y um and
I think these people have to be vetted
you know Hardware hackers right people
that are actually interested in hacking
it or whatever but I think that extra
$2,000 would really help because that
gives you a couple days of like all
right well you know there goes the
opportunity cost problem that I had and
even at the end of those couple days I
could write up my you know approach to
doing this so that the team if they're
really interested in securing it could
actually put some you know blockers in
place like an encrypted partition or
like you know whatever
um and then so there would be benefit
for them on that front as well but then
that also solves some of the upstart
problem for us and then we can start
zoning in a little bit more on on the
actual hacking portion of that rather
than just the setup but also on the
other side of this you know Matt I've
seen some of your videos where you go
from like zero to I have firmware in
like an hour and a half um so I think
maybe it could also be a skill issue you
know on on this side where it takes me
like eight hours to 16 hours to actually
like get firmware um so I mean is that
how often do you let me ask you that
because you've you've assessed a ton of
of Hardware devices what what is your if
you had to just sort of rough shot it
what is your average time to um firmware
yeah so I'm always going to go down a
cascading uh list of steps that are more
and more extreme in nature to get at
that firmware right like because first
if I can get a UR shell on a device that
gives me more than just fir because that
gives me the ability to debug the device
while it is while it is running and that
has even more benefits that that allows
me to you know understand it makes it
much more again gray or white box of an
assessment than that completely Black
Box assessment or if I'm just doing
static firmware analysis if I can't get
that then I am going to go to that
method of pulling a chip off of a device
and yeah I guess that is a thing that
helps over time with experience that
I've just pulled enough devices out of
e-waste I mean that's literally how I
practice this stuff is I find devices
out of East Goodwill or if you have a
workplace that has big East Bin you just
grab a bunch of devices and then you
don't care if you brick it right right
you can practice you know uh you know
desoldering and soldering the chip back
on all day long but you only get one
shot though too if you just have one
copy of it right like that's that's the
thing that I that gives me anxiety like
you know I would love to I loved an
event where they gave us like six of the
devices I was like six this is great I
can brick
three of these and be tot fine like I
just felt so much more um emboldened at
that event to like try stuff and and you
know not be anxious about it especially
when these devices can be pretty
expensive um but yeah I think that's a
great approach to like learn how to you
know pull chips off and stuff like that
is doing the E-Waste thing that's that's
pretty solid yeah and the and the other
thing you get out of uh you know
targeting those devices or like older
Wi-Fi router you get off of eBay you do
get uh softer targets to to look at to
kind of build up those hardw reverse
engineering exploitation skills that you
know if you're in a live hacking event
the device is going to be a little bit
more hardened than your average device
that you pick up out of an eway spin
right yeah for sure but it's I mean you
still get surprised what you see
sometimes like not naming any names but
there have been events where that has
been really surprising to me um all
right so one last little problem with
with iot hacking I just specialization
that I wanted to discuss was like it
costs a lot of money to get started in
iot hacking right like so this is mostly
oriented this this question is mostly
oriented towards like or for the for the
people that are already experienced web
or mobile hackers that want to also get
into this space right um You have to buy
a ton of devices and a ton of like um
equipment and and all that sort of thing
which can get pretty expensive on the on
just the upstart cost before you can
even have a device to hack um do you
think what do you think is like the bare
minimum setup and what are you doing
with that bare minimum setup to get
started with with the hardware hacking
stuff speaking to you know an
experienced mobile or web pen tester
yeah so I would say yeah there are tiers
that you can get into of like more
advanced gear but you do not need to
start there right there are some basic
devices uh or sorry equipment that you
can get to get yourself started and I go
back to what I said about iot testing it
starts as blackbox and you can start an
iot assessment or you know bug bounty
hunting on a device without any of this
Hardware hacking gear it's only going to
get you more insight into hacking the
device um but I would say the first
thing let me you said you said that
before and you've said that even off air
before this when we were talking but I
want to double click into that a little
bit like what are you doing are you just
like and mapping it and like looking at
the services and like playing around
with the if you're going to do a true
blackbox assessment like that without
any hardware hacking stuff like what
would that look like so sometimes you'll
find web interfaces right and so as a
web hacker you're like oh hey web
interface just on an embedded device I
understand that and uh it's just it's
just it's just a web server that might
have command injection because they do
sketchy stuff they do sketchy stuff and
maybe it's running as root who knows you
know uh yeah never seen that before have
you no no no never yeah that's why you
you mentioned uh privilege escalation
that doesn't really happen very often in
iot because if you get a shell you're
you're just right you're
rude it's impossible to do privileg
escalation some of them are so immune
because everything runs is everything
just is that's hilarious dude so um yeah
so you're you're you're hacking the the
the web application what else you got
yeah so the other thing it goes all back
to my
roots data in transit right so not just
targeting the system and what services
it has but what is that system
communicating over the internet to its
Cloud servers to its apis and stuff like
that is it shooting data over over the
network in clear Tex HTTP like like I
mentioned like back in the day back in
the Golden Age of Facebook uh you know
account poning uh there are still iot
devices that will just blast data over
the internet and clear text un all sorts
of consequences that you can have uh
that will come from that and then and
then you take that data and you're
learning more and more about uh about
the device and about the whole iot
system as a whole um and then if it's
encrypted are they doing certificate
validation correctly so all all the
stuff that uh we're probably going to
get into about about certificate
validation in in the TLs context or the
SSL
context that can all be done in a
completely blackbox test you can have no
access to the device and attempt to man
in the middle of the traffic o that is
flying over the network
and then if you if you see anything then
you can start playing around with okay
well I've got an access token here or
maybe I don't even see any traffic here
but I see the SSL certificate you know
host name or whatever right and I start
playing around with that server and that
all gives you stuff to keep in your
notes because then when you do get the
firmware the first thing you want to do
if you see an SSL connection to a server
you're like okay I have a host name now
can I go into the firmware and find out
where that request is being generated
what binary what program is creating
that request the find the request game I
love that from Sam herb like like that
was one of the one of the pivotal
moments for me collaborating with with
Sam herb was like he's like yeah
whenever I'm reversing enterprise
software I always play the can I find
this request game where I where I see
some request that comes through and then
I you know I go into the the software
you know that we reverse engineered
whatever figure out where that request
originated from and trace it all through
and that's the same thing we do there um
yeah no that that that makes sense I
didn't even really think about the fact
see this is what I'm what I'm talking
about like just understanding how the
the various attack perspectives even for
these uh iot devices right because you
have you've got like um you've got
adjacent Network right you're on the
same land and you can can you pone it
from there can you pone it with physical
access to the device can you pone it can
you pone the server that's that's
communicating with the device that you
know there is no user land thing even
really like this is the device calling
back to it you know Home Server um so
there's lots of different perspectives
from which you can Bluetooth yeah
Bluetooth again that adjacent Network
context that includes Bluetooth Wi-Fi uh
all of those type of so not even just
Lan or like Wi-Fi related stuff internet
related stuff you also all categorized
in CVSs as adjacent Network so yeah that
that all is really good scope to hammer
the Bluetooth stuff is really
interesting too man I I I thought that
it was going to be a lot more
complicated than it was when I took a
look at it um it there it is not hard to
get up started in that with just like a
mobile app that you can install on your
phone and just write various properties
into this you know yeah n NRF connect
yeah on any mobile phone iOS or Android
although iOS has some weird permissions
that it won't let you see the MAC
address of the device you're connecting
with but you can still like communicate
with it yeah it's iOS being really oh my
gosh yeah it'll show some weird U like U
uid or uid or whatever it won't actually
show you the MAC address of the device
they're like no you are not allowed to
see
you are not allowed freaking Apple Man
classic apple okay so yeah um I want the
next section that I wanted to hop into
was this one regarding one of your
recent videos uh decrypting SSL to
Chinese Cloud servers that did really
well by the way congratulations on that
video doing so well um and one of the
things you cover in that is exactly what
you were just talking about a moment ago
of bumping SSL on these iot devices and
um you know getting access to the
communications from that that device
calling home sending data out the back
door that sort of thing yeah um so for
me the way that I understood how that
would work normally was I need something
like a Wi-Fi pineapple or some malicious
router device that I can use to um you
know make this router connect to that
router right or whatever and and send
the traffic through that and then you
know have it come back to my computer or
whatever and that scared me a little bit
because it's a lot of like all right now
I got to get a malicious router and I
got to set all that up but when I looked
at the way you did it in this video it
was freaking beautiful man there's like
a like a 15 line config file that you
wrote that does everything and it was
just awesome so could you talk a little
bit about that methodology and what kind
of equipment SL setup you need to do
something like that absolutely so yeah
that tool on GitHub is called man inthe
middle router it's all it's doing is
it's you know duct taping together a few
different open source Linux utilities
that at when they're brought together
are going to effectively do the same
thing a Wi-Fi pineapple is going to do
it's going to set up an access point
with whatever SSID password encryption
type you want and then it's going to and
then optionally my program you can also
have like a USB to uh ethernet dongle so
if you have an Ethernet based device it
can feed into this same uh Network yeah
that's kind of the way that I thought
that you would do it was you would just
take like an ethernet cable and put it
on the WAN Port of your router or
whatever if you're attacking a router
and have that go through something so
when you're attacking routers is that
normally the way you do it or do you
like link one router to the other
somehow yeah so so with this with this
manal router program it's actually
making my Linux computer into a router
with by kind of again it's kind of
cobbling together a router but because
basically all that a router does I mean
it does some other things but the bare
minimum that a router needs it needs to
you know spin up a Wi-Fi hotspot right
so we can do that with host APD and all
your Wi-Fi routers 95% of them are doing
that under the hood anyway
gooey or mobile thats it which you
figure out once you've shed of them yeah
you're like where's the host F and the
SSID and password that's clear text on
the device or what right um so there's
that and then we have some IP tables
rules that are going to like pass the
the traffic that are going to forward
the traffic out to whatever your Wan
inter interface is and in the context of
my program The W interface means
whatever interface on your computer has
internet already right so be connected
to Wi-Fi ethernet whatever on the
Upstream side and then optionally I have
a bunch of Ip tables rules that can take
traffic that's egressing out of there
and say no no no don't go out come over
to my my TLS proxy that's going to man
in the middle all that traffic and so in
that place of that proxy program you can
run any number of things so uh so bur
Suite can run in transparent mode so you
need a transparent proxy right um so you
can use kaido but you have to put
something else front of it like man in
the middle proxy so you can have man in
the middle proxy which is a transparent
proxy and use kaido as an up y um or
this new tool that a researcher named
APO uh gave a defon talk on which is
called C mum and Co and uh the the the
advantage to this C mum tool is that it
will it will try to intercept the
requests with a number of different
tests so like let's say that the iot
device was merely checking that your CT
was signed by a uh a CA Authority that
it trusts it trusted but it didn't check
the name the CN the common name of the
certificate so if you had aert like
attacker. nm.com that was signed by let
encrypt and that device trust trust let
encrypt well then he's got a test for
that where you can can load in your your
let en Crypt signer and then it will it
will perform these tests but it will
perform all the tests and then the other
really cool thing is tool does is if it
fails if it fails to intercept right if
the device is properly performing
certificate validation it will then let
it pass through because what you'll find
a lot of time on an iot device is maybe
the device will get make request one
it'll get a response it'll parse it and
then it'll make request two and then you
know same thing in request three but
maybe it's only request three that has a
certificate validation issue well if
you're just black if if you're if you're
just doing this attack over and over
again on the first request the iot
device is never going to move through to
that state where it's making that next
request because there's lots of
different I mean it seemed when I was
reviewing this talk I was amazed because
this is essentially like like access
control like my my web brain says this
is Access Control validation for SSL you
know essentially there there's so many
things you would just assume that I
don't know why I would assume this
because this is such a terrible thing to
assume but that you know something at at
that lower level is is going through all
the checks and like you know is sticking
to the spec or whatever but that's never
what we've seen ever in the history of
security the opp it's just so smart to
look at all these edge cases you know
you can really when you watch the video
you can see how he is intimately
familiar with TLS and familiar with all
of the different spots along the way
where you know edges could be cut you
know Corners could be cut and you're not
actually you know doing the full
validation and then he built this into
this super easy to use tool um so I'll
definitely be using that I think in the
future for this sort of thing because um
if you can I mean if you can bump SSL on
those sort of things I mean it's very
impactful to be able to see what is
actually happening between the device
and the the call Home Server there's so
much weird [__] that happens there that
they never expect you to see exactly you
yeah and and again it's it's all this
untouched scope a lot of the times yeah
the the um the piece that you mentioned
about it passing through is so brilliant
as well because they abuse the retry um
you know parts of of TLS where they're
like okay something funky happened that
time let's just retry it right so he's
like do something funky do something
funky H most of the time they don't like
it if I do it more than like three or
four times so I'm gonna let him through
on this one but I'm gonna get them on
the next one you know it it was very it
was very well built I've got in here the
the various lists of of um you know
attacks that they do with this software
um very cool shout out also to loopin
who who uh brought this to me uh when it
was first released he was like dude this
is crazy like all of these mobile apps
are like not doing any validation at all
and and I was like oh okay cool L you
know I didn't I never went back to it
until I watched his video and I was like
oh of course like iot men in the
middling this makes so much sense um so
yeah Lupin you you you you were early on
that man you you rocked it um Okay so
we've got okay so just coming back to
your your router thing really quick
you've got this beautiful like I mean
the thing's like 15 lines but it it
spins up a DNS mask you know thing to
deal with dhtp and then you've got the
that's the part I left out about what
you need in a router you need a dhtp
server because who does static IPS noway
right exactly so you've got your DHCP
three lines of DNS mask config you've
got your host APD like 10 lines of
config I just wanted to just give you a
public shout out here on this because
this shows true understanding and true
Mastery of these things when you're able
to make it this Bare Bones and this
simple right because as hackers the more
complexity we have the more like noise
that we have it prevents us from seeing
the edge cases and the the um what's
truly being happening you know behind
the scenes right so when you have
something so simple and beautiful that
just routes everything through it just
makes me so happy um so when I saw this
I was really really excited and I think
that this reduces a lot of the friction
needed to start man in the- middling
these iot devices so thank you so much
for that and then I I just want to
clarify some of the requirements for
this so obviously you need a Linux
device right whether that's going to be
a Linux desktop or or a laptop you
probably need something dual booted so
it's like actually at the OS level um
yeah you could you could in theory do
this on a VM you just need to do USB
pass through yeah yeah yeah I I I need
to figure out how to do this with um
with WSL because I switched to WSL and
it it's a little bit dicey man like yeah
no no promises on WSL it it seriously
and it it works so well like 90% of the
time but there's just like that little
extra bit that I'm like ah wouldn't it
be really cool if I could do this but
this is need really needs to be native
Linux sort of thing so I do miss my my
my dual booted computer for that so I
will say as a hardware hacker yeah being
native on Linux it just it makes it
makes sense for me because that's where
I live um most of the devices I'm
targeting if they're not a
microcontroller they are Linux based or
some Android you know some derivative
really good too what are you using for
your like um Window Manager within Linux
oh yeah so so I run Arch Linux like like
a crazy person running Arch Lin here
um and uh I run I3 which is a like a
tiling Window Manager uh I'm basically a
complete Linux snob when it comes to all
that stuff when you said Arch and I3 I
was like okay get off my
PO um okay and the other things you need
I mean do you need any sort of special
wireless card for this like I feel like
this is not something you can do you
don't but in practice you might want one
um laptop Wi-Fi drivers I have
experienced this with the poor triers
who have had to triage my bugs that
involve Wi-Fi I'm sorry for that um uh
it's who knows what your Wi-Fi driver
what capabilities it will have and won't
have on Linux and so what I like to use
always for the Wi-Fi just for consistent
experience is a good uh Alpha so Alpha
makes USB wireless cards and you want to
get one and again Linux wi-fi this is a
pain you want to get one with a Medi
Tech driver so I can I can give you a
link to leaving the show notes if people
want a good suggestion seen these yeah
I've seen these before yeah Alpha Alfa
yeah so those are pretty much like the
hacker go go-to and if you have a
mediatech uh you know chipset it will
work out of the box on pretty pretty
much any Linux drro and because you need
different capabilities to depending on
which attack you're doing for for for
for this setup for the man inthe middle
router setup you just need to be able to
put it into Master mode which is like AP
mode in Linux but if you want to do
wi-fi hacking then you might want to do
things like have packet injection where
you can spoof the MAC address that it's
sending as and things like that so there
are different attacks and th that
adapter is going to versatile you is
going to be a used for any of that stuff
so you um you had also here on the sort
of list of requirements for this a USB
ethernet adapter and I'm wondering why
you you do that because I feel like you
can just use your ethernet port often
times to be able to you could use you
can use your onboard ethernet if you
aren't already using that
for yeah I'm yeah so I'm usually like
sitting at my at my desk at home and I
have ethernet just because it's more
reliable and so uh my Upstream internet
will be uh taking up the ethernet gotta
so you want to have another oneop yeah
that makes sense very cool man yeah no
that's there's lot lots of uh lots of
uses for all of this stuff as well you
know lots of ways you can apply it so I
think it's I think it's worth the
investment for me to grab one of these
Alpha um cards just for consistency as
well and I'll keep that in mind you said
it was mediatech drivers the mediatech
drivers are much better on Linux um yeah
you'll have all sorts of problems with
other Wireless drivers it's one of those
things on Linux it's uh yeah yeah I
appreciate that you speak to that
because whenever you get those sort of
incompatibilities I think those are the
times when I've been the most frustrated
in my entire life is when I've got
something like a driver like some device
that just won freaking work between like
freaking yuntu you know it's like this
is like the most popular Linux drro like
how am I having this problem right and
um and I I think there have been times
where I've literally spent multiple days
trying to deal with just setup issues
like that and I just have to walk away I
I don't ever get that frustrated but no
know and it definitely drives people
away from the Linux Community but what
what are you going to do yeah you got to
figure it out you know and then I think
once you get a better understanding of
some of these things you go through that
trial by fire it becomes a lot more
doable and I haven't run into issues
like that in a couple years and I'm
really grateful for that because it's
it's a pain in the ass sometimes for me
it's actually a lot of times it's it's
dual booting stuff I'll get myself into
a pickle with like grub and like trying
to get things to like I just I just hate
it or you'll update Windows and it'll
like what it did man it it'll be like
grub you don't need this yeah like what
is
that I am the only operating system
clearly you don't Windows come on all
right man um yeah I think for any of you
is just I'll just shout to the audience
real quick for any of you that haven't
seen this video decrypting uh SSL to
Chinese Cloud servers um you know it's
it's really you know it's a very Niche
thing that he's working on here but I
think a lot of the the the principles
are very widely applicable to iot
hacking so if you're looking to men in
the- Middle these devices I think this
is a really cool video for that so we'll
link that down in the description as
well definitely check that out um the
next section that I wanted to move on to
was the General iot hacking methodology
I've been holding off asking you
questions today as we've been hanging
out a little bit before this episode but
I'm really excited to dive into this so
um when you are approaching a device
obviously you've got your ways of
getting um a shell on the device prior
to pulling the chip off right you've got
your uart you've got JTAG um you got
like glitching at into those two things
right yeah um and so I'm wondering what
what time what do you try before you
switch to a chip off methodology and and
you know effectively break your device
there but we'll come back to that
because there are some nuances with that
yeah oh yeah um yeah so so uh uart is
always going to be my first goal on any
device um I guess we got to talk about
devices in two different categories
because one there's a microcontroller a
and Os like Linux
orid and so I I treat those two very
differently in my process a
microcontroller if you if you found the
lucky device that they didn't disable
JTAG on then you can use JTAG to dump
the firmware and that is the way to dump
the firmware and then if JTAG is locked
then glitching is the way to glitch the
system into unlocking J tag or or the
read whatever readout you know protocol
is being used so um but that methodology
I am not experienced with I I tend to to
to uh favor and Target the Linux based
devices a lot more uh glitching is
something I want to learn and get into
more it's a very Advanced skill and kind
of like I talked about how there's
people who just focus on like Hardware
security there are people who like
everything they do is glitching chips
and and pulling firmware off of them
engineer mic when you're when you're
talking about microcontrollers versus I
guess micro computers or like micro
actual you know Linux systems yes um
yeah I mean on some of these boards
there there may not even be a core OS
for you to get very much off of right
correct it's just like a board you know
with with its own firmware attached to
it there not running uh a you know an OP
a very minimized version of Linux like
which is what we often see and then you
know even further there's like okay
you're actually run running like a strip
down version of Android or whatever um
that's a good differentiation I like
that I will say in the microcontroller
case uh I I I I might even tend to jump
to chip off faster if and this is a big
if so microcontrollers have built-in
flash pretty much all of them do but
they optionally can have external flash
and so if it if it's external flash then
it's just a flash chip like any other
flash chip you can pull it off pop it in
your Universal programmer and you can
read that that that firmware out that so
I've never hacked a micro controller
I've always hacked uh microcomputers you
know um stripped down Linux versions or
whatever so when you're dealing with a
microcontroller what kind of stuff can
you expect to get off not very much not
very much without uh again very involved
reverse engineering which again being
really honest like like in a bug bouty
context where you are considering Roi
and like like like time money like like
is this going to pay off it might not
right might not um there is uh a case
though there are always exception to
these rules cuz uh I believe the bug of
mine that we're going to talk about that
has performed on a microcontroller so um
occasionally you can find files or or
something like that but what you're
going to be looking at the firmware is
going to be a binary blob because if you
think about what a microcontroller is I
I I again I'm from the Linux world right
so I think of everything through that
lens so how I like to think of a
microcontroller is it's one static
program like think if there was only one
process you know binary exactly and when
you boot up the the processor it starts
the program and when that program exits
the CPU halts wow right like like that
and so and so that's why you know when
you're coding a microcontroller you have
like an infinite Loop right and then you
you know you call various threads or do
your stuff um but it's always running
that one process me to think about that
even like yeah I I so think about that
whole ecosystem from a Linux and Os
perspective as well and you think that
there's this thing called a file system
which sometimes they build in sometimes
there are these uh microprocessor os's
you know that where they will build out
the concept of a of a file system that
that can exist on a microcontroller but
most of the time that's not a thing gez
dude that's crazy so a lot of this stuff
is just getting held in in memory and H
yeah yeah but if you can if you can
extract that firmware and you see things
like Secrets or uh certificates uh like
like well like talk about in our finding
down the road uh you can maybe do
something with that maybe you can do
firmware modification maybe you can grab
those secrets and then uh or URLs right
if you see API endpoints any kind of
clear teex string you're going to look
at that and right DD and strings is your
friend there people ask me all the time
like oh you're this like really Advanced
like iot hacker how do you find that
password in that program did you reverse
I ran
strings like half the time literally the
first first thing I do if I get a binary
blob I run strings pipe it into less and
then I just hit the down page uh button
on my keyboard what what what are you
doing with less man you got to pipe it
into a Vim buffer and then it like oh
geez what what get what are we doing I
know oh my gosh okay so so very good
differentiation I'm really glad you you
brought that up because there those are
definitely two different worlds right
yeah so back to the Linux path because I
think this is where some of these skills
really come into use more so so my first
goal is uart because uart gives me more
than just the firmware if I if if I get
a good Art Shell so when you connect
when you find your art interface right
uart is a Serial protocol that allows
you to communicate over you know you
know some some Vol some digital signal
over a voltage you know maybe usually
3.3 volts so you connect up your cable
so we go back to what equipment do you
need my first piece of Hardware hacking
equipment I would ever suggest is a
multimeter and a 3.3 Vol uh uart to USB
cable yeah that is going to help you get
so much on so many devices that the ROI
on that is just that seems and it's like
a $15 cable and it's pretty Universal
too you know any hardware hacker that
I've talked to is like yeah man just get
a multimeter and a and a UR cable and
you know you're you're good a very large
portion of the time yeah maybe a
soldering iron because sometimes they
take the they they don't populate the
pins and the production devices so you
have to put a little you know like you
know half a cent pin and soldered on but
yeah yeah so so um when you're
identifying you are are you often doing
that from the data sheet are you just
kind of like poking around on the on the
device with the multimeter are you I
mean obviously you you know after a
little while you kind of get a trained
die for it you can say okay that's like
four to six pins or whatever right there
um it and it's four to six right no it
can
be it's it's depend but if you see two
things that look like connectors on the
board the one with more p is J taged one
less is you are but yeah it's all it's
all pattern recognition like I can just
look at a board and be like okay there's
the flash there's the ram there's the
CPU you know over time you do get that
trained eye and that's why I really
always suggest people go dig through
E-Waste and just like open up devices
even if you just open up the device and
look at it you're gaining something
because you're looking and you identify
the components on the board because
you're you're getting those reps in to
be like okay there's art there's the
flash chip those are the things that I
care about this is the same thing we
tell new web hackers is you don't even
have to hack anything you don't have to
try anything just get start looking at
htttp requests as they come through the
proxy and start understanding what that
does as as correlated to the action that
you just performed in the web browser
right if you can categorize those
requests and start understanding okay
anything Sentry related you know or
whatever like that's that's metrics I
don't need to look at that super much
it's funny because that contradicts what
I said last week about about Sentry
being an interesting attack surface
which it is but you see you know if
you're focusing not for the new hackers
exactly if you're a new hacker you want
to you know zone right in on the the
functional API that's that's targeting
the main website right and I think this
is the hardware version of that of like
break these break these things open um
start identifying all the various
components know that's a flash chip know
that might be a UR connector you know
that sort of thing exactly exactly yeah
yeah the things I'm looking for on a
board are art and the Flash chip that's
it on a Linux based system I'm not
really worried about J tag at at all
honestly I'm just kind of leaving that
by the wayside um with art then I'm then
I'm going if I if I if I see something
that I think is uart I'm turning on that
device I'm probing with my multimeter
with ground I find ground somewhere uh
Wi-Fi uh antennas or always connected
ground you find you find shields that
are grounded and I'm probing the pins to
find a voltage that fluctuates
especially on boot and that's probably
the transmit pin uh and then usually
next door to that pin uh to the right or
the left I found weird devices where
it's somewhere else you'll find the rece
you'll find the receive pin where where
you from your Ur cable are going to
transmit to it so you've got transmit
you've got receive you've got some
voltage one what is it what is the so
you don't need VCC that's only if you're
going to be powering the device over the
U cable which usually doesn't work
anyway so you actually want to just
completely ignore that yeah and
sometimes I think people have been like
don't mess with that Port because it'll
blow your if you hook it up to the wrong
thing it'll like screw your USB port on
your laptop it it might do something bad
just just just leave it alone don't
touch that Justin is what I've heard um
Okay cool so you identify that um you
give that a shot that doesn't work JTAG
is is disabled we could go the glitching
route but more often we're going to go
the chip off Route exactly um and so
that process as far as I look as I know
about it and and maybe you can sort of
walk me through that is um you get like
a hot air station and you are you know
fluxing this thing up the the flash chip
you have to identify the flash chip
first right y you're you're hitting it
with hot air until you're able to pull
it off right yes and then you're
cleaning the chip off getting it in good
shape putting it into a chip reader yeah
um and then hopefully you'll be able to
just read that chip just like the actual
system would um as it's booting up and
then you can you know access all the
various partitions and file structures
that they have on that device um how
often is it that
simple it's I would say it is usually
that simple assuming that you have the
right reader so almost like Step Zero in
that process before I ever shoot hot air
and I talk about this on my videos is
just like read the serial number on the
chip and make sure you have the right
device like to to take it off because
especially in the context right where uh
you are new and starting out you don't
want you don't want to unnecessarily
brick a device uh because you pulled the
chip off and you're like oh well I don't
have a reader for this now and I got to
go order one from China or whatever it's
yeah it's going to take long time to get
here um yeah so I would ident I I always
read the chip cial or you know the the
the identify the model number I go and I
look in my software so the the chip
reader I use for everything that's not
emmc based stuff is going to be the XU
uh
T56 that is a universal programmer it's
got tons of different sockets that it
can me uh can fit into it it actually
does do uh emmc chips now um yeah I was
going to say so if you're not talking
about an emmc chip what is is this like
a flash chip that you're what is this
other alternative I I've only hacked
emmc yeah so emmc is only on like
high-end Android devices or like yeah
it's it's it's usually where you're
going to have more storage on board the
system a cheaper iot devices are going
to have Nan flash chips or even spy
flash um which are just slower right um
and uh usually don't have as much
capacity they can emmc chips they kind
of hook up I mean you can almost I've
seen some some people mention that you
can kind of wire them into an SD card
reader itself like you can literally
connect the some of the the pieces on
the the the um what are they called the
plates or whatever on those directly
into a USB to micro USB converter and
it'll read like an SD card it it it it
like it like fundamentally is an SD card
in a different shape yeah yeah yeah so
that that that's pretty cool about that
um and then there's this new kind of
chip uh called ufs which it looks
exactly like emmc but your normal emmc
reader can't can't read it so I've ran
into that before yeah that's tricky but
those I've got I've got another reader
for that but again I'd say this ex geu
platform it is I mean it's got some
sketchy like Chinese software that you
have to run in Windows or I run it under
wine because I'm you know I like to stay
in Linux right okay yeah um but I
uh yeah I'm I'm a snob it's okay I'll
own it um I I like that programmer
because it does the the widest amount of
type of types of chips out there and I
just have to get one device I have to
buy new sockets occasionally to fit
different chips and stuff like that yeah
because there's like there's like little
molds or whatever right that you or at
least this is my experience with the
with the um emmc chips where you know
you have to get it in a specific mold
and then you put it in there and that
aligns everything properly so it can
read up through those those uh those
ports um yeah that's you need you need
some specialized stuff for that so yeah
yeah so in the in the like you know
electrical engineering world it's called
the package so the package type defines
like the shape it defines the geometry
of the of of the Chip And then emmc is
even weirder because you'll have the
same pin out on the bottom but there'll
be different dimensions of the Chip And
then so you'll have these different like
guiding rails that you put into your
emmc reader yeah that's what I'm talking
about okay and so in the Nan you know
Nan flash world or in other those other
things you actually have to have the the
the layout of the pins is different on
the bottom and so you actually have to
have specialized adapters for that or
yeah so the universal programmer it has
basically a a set interface and then it
has different sockets that all fit this
one common interface and so the software
inside this Universal programmer is
smart enough to know like you configure
the software so instead of like the emmc
reader where you can just like it just
can mount onto your onto your Linux
computer like like like like it's a mass
storage device or SD card right uh these
other types of reads you have to read it
out through the software and it
literally just gives you the firmware
file and it's not partitioned so you
have to go through there and use bin
usually you can use walk and it'll just
it'll just extract the file system okay
gotcha so you're getting just a Big Blob
out of that um and then you're you're
you're not actually looking at a whole
file system or whatever you're having to
extract that file system and binw can
get messy sometimes too it can it can
there's another there's another tool
called un blob I I I swear every every
like six months I like you know we like
curse binw walk and be like I need to
just not do anything else for like you
know like for like at least a quarter
and just like program a new tool that
does it better a new binw yeah yeah dude
it's probably so much harder than we
think it is it is it is you B I'm so
sorry like you are amazing yeah they are
they're awesome um that's great that's
great Okay so so we go down that process
we do the chip off we load it up into
our reader we get either you know this
this Big Blob and we binwalk it extract
the file system or we just mount it like
an SD card and read off all the various
partitions or whatever yeah um we look
around we identify the main partition we
start you know we we can we can mount it
just CD into it start playing around
start reading all these config files
grapping for Secrets getting our hands
on source code hopefully um and and uh
so once we do that are you
like where do you go post exploitation
most of the time are you looking at like
Network Services are you looking at the
way that that device communicates back
up to the the you know home the mother
server whatever you know like you know
that's running this Fleet of iot devices
um what is your go-to approach from
there yeah so it's definitely
contextualized based on the iot device
but I'd say those are my two approaches
right it's what network services are
available on the device and uh what
communication again again again like
like data and Transit I love looking and
understanding data and Transit and if
there so okay so if if I have a device
where it is doing all the SSL
verification correctly and I haven't yet
been able to Peak inside of that traffic
I can either statically analyze the
firmware to understand what types of
requests can be made to those Cloud
servers or if I've got the skills to
reattach the chip I can patch in my own
CA certificate and then I can put the
chip back on and now it trusts my
certificate uh and and and now I can now
I can use man middle proxy I can use
whatever one of those transparent
proxies to inter the we're gonna we're
going to talk about the BGA reballing
and that remounting later so we'll we'll
hold that for now yeah but that applies
to any kind of chip that technique will
apply to any kind of chip which is way
easier when it's not BG right so think
think a spy flash chip just has eight uh
legs it just has eight legs yeah it
doesn't have
153 you know pin pads at the bottom and
the legs are Exposed on the sides of the
chip so these are probably like the
easiest to you don't even need a hot air
gun you could you could one at a time
with a soldering iron reattach yeah yeah
yeah you could you could do that to put
it back on W I've actually seen some
hackers get like these little mini clips
that they use to like clip onto those
legs and then you can just
essentially like cuz it's just
electrical signals going over that you
know reading out of there so when it
boots up you could justo and just slurp
up the data yeah so you can do that I
love my I love my my technical hacker uh
you know sound there that I may slurp uh
no that's great that's awesome so those
clips there's some pros and cons of
those so obviously if it works the pro
is you didn't have to desolder the chip
off the board and you still have a
functional device right right the con is
that sometimes uh when you're doing that
read it it actually is sending power
from your reader and it's trying to
because it is powering on the chip and
sometimes it can like inadvertently
power on different circuits but in an
unexpected way and it just won't either
either won't work I mean in really rare
cases you might blow something but that
probably not okay um and also sometimes
where you just have to chip off it
practically the equipment is is pretty
expensive I think for that too so I
think the um yeah especially when it's
simple and you've got like you know
eight points that you need to solder
back on yeah it may not be that bad of
you just pull it off and then resolder
it back on afterwards yeah especially
once you get a little bit more familiar
with how to do this soldering thing
because for me I mean the only soldering
experience that I that I have um is
getting essentially soldering on those
little connectors so you can connect up
to art or whatever and uh and so I think
that's a little bit more intimidating to
me
but but I think uh I think flux is the
magic of all the reattachment right flux
is just this magical substance that
makes the solder go where it's supposed
to go dud I think every Hardware hacker
has like this amazing image of flux
every everyone's like man they'll just
sit down and I'll be like hey guys let's
talk about Hardware hacking they're like
have you ever heard of flux like flux is
the [__] dude like it just makes
everything I'm like okay listen guys
like can we move along from the flux
please um it's so funny dude uh okay so
I guess I'm I'm gonna I'm gonna push you
again on that last question though so if
you had to pick one or the other let's
say it is a it is a call home device so
there is some sort of cloud management
um are you first going to go after the
network service or you're G to go after
the call home stuff I think this goes
back to how I think I I am always
interested in data and Transit and so
I'm always going to look at that traffic
going out and try going out and trying
to understand those API
I think that's where the impact is too
you know because if you can pop
something up in the cloud then you can
pone all the devices exactly imagine
imagine if there's like in the in those
call home API requests there's an idor
and now you can now you can make a
request on behalf of any device imagine
that yeah there would be an idor in
those devices I know right yeah so that
you're right that's where the bigger
impact can lie and so that's where I
want to Target first but the Network
Services I I mean again I'm I'm going to
be doing all these in assessment and
going down every tracking once you once
you get firmware how important is it to
you to get a dynamic shell like so you
can do Dynamic analysis of what's
happening on the device it's moderately
important I I I I I can totally you know
do static reverse engineering all day I
like doing you know static analysis I
actually really rarely will connect up
GDB but rce isn't my best V class
actually that that that I'm the best at
so I'm better at like reverse
engineering weird binary protocols I
don't know like I said I get I get the
dopamine Rush from when the only thing
standing in between you and absolutely
poning something is understanding how
the stupid protocol custom protocol that
some engineer invented out of hul cloth
right yeah roll rolled their own crypto
and everything into it it's like oh my
god um yeah that that makes sense okay
so Moder important to get sh but it it
does help it has huge benefit right
because sometimes you'll be rever you'll
be doing your static analysis and you'll
be like I just don't understand or maybe
you know gedra or whatever other reverse
engineering binary reversing tool is
giving you a pain in one spot and if you
can just log into that shell and see
what's actually going on on the device
like oh it's writing a file here but I
don't really understand what the file
contents look like I could spend eight
hours reverse engineering the static
binary to figure out what it's writing
into that
the and look at it's writing into the F
right yeah yeah it's so it's so helpful
uh once we have like the device that I'm
I'm talking about it was just talk just
getting getting the shell dude was just
unbelievably helpful like and and I know
I did another interview with um one of
the guys from Pon to own sinology and um
you know he talked about the importance
of to him of getting you know dynamic
analysis on these devices because he's
specifically looking for RC Zer days um
and you know you really have to to be
able to get in there and sort of
dynamically debug it's going to save you
so much time yeah um so I think I think
depending on what kind of approach you
have there's a different there's a
different route that you might take
there um but I for that for that exploit
development that is necessary I would
say it's necessary to get that to get so
it depends on your goal if you're
looking for a zero day on the device
firmware that's good but I think
oftentimes in a a bug Bounty context
we're just looking for Maximum Impact
right so getting an idor in the the
mother server of the iot devices right
um uh is actually way more impactful
because not only can we just pop this
one device we can pop all the devices
potentially I I like that um okay so I I
wanted to ask you this one as well what
does you know after after you're you're
on the device you've got some some some
grip on the device whether it be
firmware whether it be a dynamic shell
whatever
um what kind of post exploitation attack
vectors do we need to think about there
like you mentioned getting access to you
know API keys or whatever so we can talk
to the mother server um what other
things might uh web hackers and mobile
hackers that aren't thinking in this iot
hacking realm yet not realize is
extremely important when actually you
know the rubber meets the road you've
got the firmware now it's vul time you
know what I'm saying yeah no I I would
say yeah the the attack surface is yeah
we've already talked about data and
Transit we talked about Network Services
I would say within that category of
Network Services right you have
the common Network Services that they're
going to be more used to the web based
ones and then there's going to be all
this custom stuff that's going
to uh lead them into binary reverse
engineering and just to understand how
the whole system works there's a lot of
binary reverse engineering you you
you're very rarely going to
find uh I say this uh and and I know
what you're gonna think when I say this
you're very rarely going to find python
on an iot device yeah y but sometimes
there's an exception to every rule I'm
like put that it's slow it's slow right
and that's why they don't do it but
maybe when you have a lot of resources
on a system it's fine um but the other
thing that I'm looking at is again
thinking in that adjacent category
Bluetooth right Bluetooth Wi-Fi any kind
of RF uh that that chips that are on the
device that there is code on the device
that will process that input and and
give an output right so breaking this
down you know you're saying
don't don't necessarily just focus on
the communication you know HTTP based
oftentimes communication between the
device and and the mother server or um
just focusing on the web application
that's that's being exposed on this
device also look at these these more
these more binary level protocols and
understand what function these play in
the bigger ecosystem of the device right
and and how to affect the business logic
use cases of this device via those
protocols absolutely abolutely and and
yeah it's especially in those protocols
where you will find that the only
security that is being implemented is uh
security through obscurity right it's
it's it's just that oh this is a weird
custom protocol or process or something
like that and that's really what's
providing the security to the system
I've seen this so much too like
sometimes these things will literally
just shell out you know to like to like
a binary that's on the system and it's
like oh my gosh so just diving deeper
into um what's happening on the back end
of all these services and on even on the
web stuff um really really impactful and
then I think also sometimes there's like
device to device uh communication that's
happening you know if you've got like an
a uh you know a mobile app that can also
connect to this you know diving into
that mobile app and then understanding
how that communication is happening
Bluetooth or whatever the other day I
was literally uh testing an iot device
and I also was listening to Spotify
which will scan your local network which
will broadcast across your local network
and look for UPnP Services running on
devices and it was like contacting this
iot device that I was looking at and I'm
like what the heck like Spotify please
stop that yeah but it's like oh okay
there's up on this or so yeah there
there there is uh again in that local
network context you're right so mobile
app
Communications to the device or device
to device Communications if you have uh
so so for that you want to think of if
there's a company that has multiple
devices that are in this ecosystem where
they talk to each other and they have
all these cool Integrations with each
other you might have to go buy another
device to to observe there there might
be a code path that you will never
actually see until you possess this
other device and put it on the same
network and then they all of a sudden
start talking to each other I'll be
explicit about this because it's it's a
well-known protocol that's way out there
but um Amazon sidewalk protocol is
really because itess isy to replicate
what they've done with um the find your
iPhone like you know Network essentially
of devices that have this devic to
device communication that provides very
minimal data but will also allow you to
just sort of identify your device
wherever it is yeah and like I was
reading the spec for this thing and it's
like whoa this is super weird um because
and there's a white paper out there you
can read the whole thing they're very
public about how this is a secure
protocol um but essentially it's
allowing the your phone that has no
relationship to this other device or or
whatever other device to send HTTP
requests as a proxy through these Amazon
devices I'm like wow this is like ssrf
you know if I can figure out a way to
get this to connect to any host like
this is really bad um and and obviously
you know they've done their due
diligence trying to engineer it in a way
that that is um you know more secure for
that but that was a real eye opener for
me as it as it pertains to
um devic to device communication and
what kind of stuff they try to build
into these to create these seamless
product experiences that we take for
granted in a lot of context like like
the Spotify thing right where it's
communicating with all the other you
know Google home devices that are like
you know allowing me to control my
Spotify from any device in the house you
know uh you take that stuff for for
granted but then when you start
assessing those sort of products it's
like oh this is really
sketchy yeah another thing I want to
mention uh talking about yeah strategy
when I'm going after a device I think it
was on your last podcast you talked
about the the pros and the cons of like
the the setup process or the
initialization of an account and whether
or not you should focus on that I will
say in the iot context there are some
bugs or there are some requests that
will only go out the first time the
device ever is set up and there's a lot
you can learn from that uh and and like
like I I found a device that even after
factory reset it would never again send
an HTTP request because it kept
something in the firmware that persisted
that some piece of information in the
firmware that pers persisted across
factory reset so I only caught the
request using my man- in-the middle
router setup the first time the device
ever connected to the internet so uh
with iot devices another big uh maybe
maybe I'd call this an attack Vector but
the bootstrapping process how does the
device get its initial connection to the
internet right so there's a lot of
different choices that an iot
manufacturer here we're considering a
like a Wi-Fi based iot device right so
that device obviously needs some way to
get your Wi-Fi SSID and password so that
it can connect your network and once it
does that it can talk to its Cloud
servers and it's Off to the Races but
that bootstrapping process of how the
device gets added and again this is
never going to be some remote exploit
this is going to be Network adjacent or
physical or something like that or local
network um some devices will spin up
their own Wi-Fi access point that then
has like some API that you can then that
you then feed it the the the SSID and
password and if you can jump on there
and access some other API yeah like
services are Exposed on that interphase
or something like that it's like oh my
gosh absolutely C or or you know just I
mean there's even the risk of I mean
most devices are moving away from that
because it's a it's almost a design flaw
I find I find myself in iot system
systems uh I don't know I feel like I'm
psychoanalyzing the developers of these
iot systems because I'll find these bugs
that I'm like yeah there's no way to fix
this unless you like scrap the project
because because it's from the from the
design phase they did something that
necessitated uh initially trusting
something that is untrusted again this
bootstrapping process of how do I get
this device connected the first time
another class of of vulnerabilities
that's like that is squatting on a
serial number so let's say the device
once it connects to its cloud or its
Mothership right uh it says here's my
serial number please add me to this
user's account well what's stopping me
from just hitting that API and
registering every you know sequential
and the serial numbers are usually
sequential right and registering every
device to my account and then when the
actual user goes it says this device
error this device is already registered
right and some denial service and and
wow see that that's exactly what I'm
talking about right like that that is
the sort of attack Vector stuff that I
love to hear on this podcast right like
like the stuff that you wouldn't
necessarily or you you've developed over
years of working on this stuff that is
that is more specific to these Hardware
devices and the way that they interact
with all these Services excellent I love
that um what a cool idea and then also
there's there's also the the the resale
approach to this as well you know if you
do a factory reset or whatever I don't
know if this is an accepted bug or not
but if you do a factory reset on this
device right and you sell it and then
you are able to maintain a serial number
a key or something like that that then
allows you to take over that device
after somebody else has used it again
like is are those sort of bugs accepted
or like what are your what's your
experience I don't know about bug Bounty
programs accepting those findings um I
have definitely uh talked on my YouTube
channel at length because again I get
devices out of ewaste and then I and
then I present them on my YouTube
channel and that is uh
some of the occasional times where I
need to censor things in my video
because if I grab some device that's
added yeah like you can we're talking
about host APD yeah right if I can get
into that firmware and find that host
APD config file it's going to have the
SSID and the password in there or other
credentials and stuff like that yeah I
think you said I think in one of the
videos you said like yeah guys this is
why we shred devices when we when we get
rid of them like this is why you never
resell a device if you care about your
security because um here's this person's
access key you know or whatever yeah
there's a popular iot device out there
which I won't name that if you sell it
on eBay uh others can buy it and if you
perform chip off and you go into that
hostapd file and you you find it SS ID
and password then there's this attack
Vector where you using maybe man the
middle router you set up a Wi-Fi access
point with that same SS ID and password
well now that device is going to happily
connect and have internet access again
and what if that device still has fresh
tokens on it that where where that
device now grants you access to
somebody's account oh my go gosh D crazy
that may or may not be a thing out there
who knows who knows um I I don't I don't
know how in depth we'll go with this
question but if you've got anything on
this great if not we'll move along but
um I wanted to ask so like we talked
about already on the Pod a decent bit um
these attacks uh that we're doing on iot
devices are often limited to adjacent
Network or local right um let's say
we've got a local device um what are
some ways that you have been able to
Pivot this more into an adjacent or
remote environment um is
there I know it's kind of a a very
product specific question um and I think
probably if I were to answer it myself
what I would say is you have to have a
thorough understanding of the
application you're hacking um to
understand how to hit those code paths
but I'm wondering if you had any tricks
up your sleeve with regards to this
because things do get rated much lower
right they they they do and that is
unfortunate um one thing I've I've tried
to do in the past with mixed success
let's say I have a network service that
maybe is intended only to be accessed on
the local network and and I find a
vulnerability in that but I can prove
through using like showen or census iio
that a bunch of people are port
forwarding to this and I actually see
real iot devices of this
and I like so so what I have to do then
is find some fingerprint that makes a
good search uh on those platforms and I
can prove say no no there are actually
remotely exploitable devices of this of
this type with this service that are on
the internet and you know several
thousand of them sometimes yeah I've
definitely seen that and actually when
you said that it made me think about
something um I did hear at a talk
recently at rvac the Richmond uh
security conference talking about how a
lot of these devices you know have ufw
or whatever set up you know firewall on
their W interface and you can't access
all these ports but then on the IPv6
interface they don't have any any
firewall right so you can interact with
all of these services that are just
binded to you know star or whatever to
every interface um over IPv6 and and get
access to all of these internal services
that are not listening on the ipv4 um so
I I just and and apparently that was a
massive Trend the guys that were talking
about it at the um uh at the the talk
they they did a bunch of router
exploitation and they saw that a lot
which I was like that is terrifying as
we move to IPv6 what kind of stuff we
might run into with that yeah Microsoft
just had their big IPv6 bug I don't know
if we're ready for I IPv6 I don't know
man I it's G to be it's G to be a doozy
for sure yeah um all right last one I
had in this section was what is one area
that you could grow in as a hardware
hacker what are you trying to grow in oh
yeah that's uh like I mentioned before
it's microcontrollers and uh glitching
so they're uh so I not associated with
them at all but hex.io has some pretty
sweet Hardware hacking content coming
out and uh definitely when there's a
lull in the action for me I want to I
want to start digging into that content
because um again like I said in the
microcontroller context that's that's my
weaker area as opposed to Linux based
devices and oftentimes a necessity to
extracting the firmware from those
devices is uh glitching yeah that makes
sense yeah I think they were running I
think they were running a glitching
Workshop or something like that at at
Defcon this year they were they were
yeah so bummed I didn't make it to that
man Defcon is such a difficult thing as
a content creator as well because you're
you're pulled in the direction of
producing right like I want to give to
the community at Defcon but also there's
such cool [__] going on you know like I
I want to just go and just sit in all
these talks and I was so salty because
um a couple of the talks that I really
really really wanted to go to this year
just had hard conflicts with my own
engagements and I was like so annoying
um okay so let's go into some of the
more um Advanced Hardware stuff um uh we
can we can go to to BGA reballing at
some point but let's hit um the
certificate pinning versus Certificate
validation section first and kind of
talk about um how uh certain
minum does you know takes advantage of
that whole situation and what the
differences between those two things are
yeah so to start off I'm sure every uh
person who's looked at the scope of a
bug Bounty uh of a bug Bounty program
will see uh that certificate pinning is
out of scope on every program and mostly
you know this in the mobile device
context but it's it's it's an identical
situation in the iot context right and
so uh first we have to understand what
the differences arec and it's really
hard to understand the differences
between CT pinning and SSL like like
certificate validation let's just call
it that that um because certificate
pinning is just a stricter form of of
certificate validations so if a device
is doing certificate validation if
they're actually checking that the the
the Ser the server is presenting a
certificate that is signed by a trusted
CA in its trust chain then but it's not
pinning pinning meaning it only trusts
the leaf node the server certificate not
just any CT signed by a CA in its trust
chain um then that's fine like like
that's not a problem if they're not
doing certificate pinning and not
strictly saying hey you have to have
this exact server certificate or a hash
of it there's different ways you can
Implement a certificate pinning but if
they are doing neither of those then
that is a huge problem right it goes
from being na to like you know high or
critical depending on the context
depending on what type of information is
being communicated in that TLS uh
Channel because specifically if it's not
doing this validation correctly you just
have clear text access to everything
that's happening through that device
right exactly and it should again there
this is where you sometimes have to
argue with triers and stuff like that I
think it's getting better because
there's becoming more understanding of
these attacks but uh understanding that
that should be Network that that that
that that is a remote that is a remote
attack because although often times that
attack is going to happen on the local
network on the same subnet through ART
poisoning this is an interesting or po
or like having control of the local
router any router along the path between
the iot device and the server if any of
those is compromised right so if you
want to get crazy you can go look at
like some of the like Snowden docks of
like what the one of the NSA programs
alleged that they had the ability on
internet routers to per man the middle
of TLS traffic so if you think of a
threat actor like that they don't need
to be on your local network as long as
they're a that path that the data will
take from the iot device to the Cloud
Server where yeah I mean and think about
when you're using um you
know how many routers may be along the
path in some of these public networks
you're connecting to as well I mean it's
it's a lot it's a lot yeah if you've Le
if you run if you've ever run a trace
route you see how many routers like it's
what we're saying is that any one of
those routers if they're compromised and
and can perform this man in a middle
attack then uh that's very interesting I
wonder I wonder if that would be I
wonder what the trade-off is between uh
in CVSs between adjacent Network and or
adjacent and network versus attack
complexity High because you know what
what I'll see them do sometimes is when
you want to make these changes you'll
you'll do like you'll flip one uh of the
metrics and then add complexity high or
whatever I don't know where it stands on
it you know and obviously I I I'm in I'm
with you you know I think it should just
be Network without the int complexity
High because the risk is there but um
yeah do do you know
where yeah it's like unfortunately I
understand the attack complexity High
argument but yeah but I kind I actually
kind of understand that trade-off I hate
to say this because on the local network
it's trivial right like if somebody is
on the same subnet as you they can art
poison and get themselves in a position
of of a man in the middle quite easily
uh that is that is pretty trivial
whereas you could you could argue well
having an attacker have to compromise
some internet router that's that there
is some complex so I'm looking at it
now Jon
network will give you and in this
specific scenario that I'm looking at a
1.1 uh boost
and then if you move attack complexity
to high that will drop you down way
lower so it would it would be better for
you to have just adjacent adjacent
network with low yeah then attack
complexity high with network well I'll
know what the for couple points from now
yeah by by seven on on the scale um so I
mean you're still Landing within that
high range it's a high seven the way
that I've got it is like um
confidentiality High uh Integrity low
availability none scope changed user
interaction none privilege required none
and then I I'll switch the the network
in the attack complexity Fields um and
it looks like we're landing at like a
7.5 um on the network attack Vector with
attack complexity high and if we switch
it to adjacent network instead attack
complexity low we're looking at an 8.2
okay so I think I think um I think the
best bet there is to go adjacent Network
um we we are bug bounty hunters right
now we are strategizing on what
green hat man green hat all day let's go
um okay so so cool so the important
thing to understand here is if you can
find a problem with um the certific
validation at any in any of the services
that are working on this on this device
calling back out that could be a big
problem and um and I think there's
there's more techniques you know
obviously this this really great talk by
uh Oppo right is is really great for
that but if there's more ways for us to
sort of test the implementation of of
TLS in this environment um that's great
I mean that's that's you can really pop
some impactful bugs from that you can
and and and yeah when you're talking
about how that's going to get rated in
my experience it's always going to be
based on what kind of data is being
transferred in that right if it's just
your if it's just your metrics log
they're going to be like h no no that's
not very that's not not very impactful
but if uh if there are session tokens in
there then that's an account take that
that is account takeover right and and
and so that is going to be impactful and
so um yeah and even if there is attack
complex attack complexity high or it's
adjacent I've I've had those be critical
be scored as critical if the data in
there is really juicy yeah and you know
CVSs isn't necessarily built for that
environment either so I think talking
with the team talking understanding
their threat model is important in any
area of B County but specifically in
Hardware stuff that's important um and
yeah you know a high in uh a high in the
hardware world is like you know what
they say two birds in the high you know
I'm not even gonna I'm not even gonna
try but um but yeah you know a high in
the hardware world you know is could pay
as much as a crit in a in the web world
so and more sometimes and something uh
important to point out if you need
ammunition for your reports uh hacker
ones uh I believe it's for standards
they have updated those to include man
certificate validation and I think the
default is a high uh really yes that's
really cool so so default is a high
Depend and then you know various factors
so that's helpful if you need to include
that in your reports that's really
helpful dude actually I'm gonna look
that up right now certificate I
certificate validation that's awesome
yeah they do have that wow that's yeah
should be applied as a high and they
give you the CVSs 3.1 score very awesome
man I love that thank you hack link that
in your reports yeah that one is going
in the in the description for sure let
me just go ahead and put that in there
now so I don't forget um perfect okay
great so um before we get on to the uh
the hacking stories and and such which
I'm really looking forward to let's hit
this um this PGA reballing thing man
because I am scared as heck of that so
essentially my understanding of that is
you you've chip off you pulled a chip um
it's it's a BGA and you've cleaned it
all off you know gotten all the gunk off
there popped it into a reader probably
modify the chip in some way right like
replacing you know inserting your own
certificate as a certificate Authority
um you know maybe even uh added
something to the the the OS so that you
can get a shell or something like that
and now you are reattaching that device
you know or that chip back to the device
and then trying to boot the device back
up and have it use that chip so bad and
you're hoping you're hoping that you see
the light flash whatever is the
indicator that it's not completely
borked yeah right exactly wow that is
just such a badass technique um talk to
me a little bit about that how difficult
it is and if you have any tips for it
you said you've done it a couple times
right yeah so this is a new skill set
that I'm developing and uh that's why I
say with this Hardware hacking stuff
like you can always hack on a device
with less of the hardware hacking skills
and then build them out over time you're
just adding these tools uh to your tool
belt so uh yes I've done it about three
times successfully
ofices I've you pulls off but yeah
effectively what we
have so we have a PCB and it has so so
PCB is made uh out of etch it's etching
copper so there's a copper uh like inter
face basically to the to to your PCB and
then it cuts out around the copper it
cuts out copper so that you have all
your connection points to where your
different uh components connect to the
board and so yes so we're going to clean
the uh the the uh the pads on the chip
and we're going to clean the pads on the
board and then what we're going to do is
you're going to use these BGA and you're
cleaning them with uh solder and and
some a lot of flocks and you're trying
to just get those guys all and solder
braid or Wick and so that's that's just
a metal substance that or you know like
like that you that you heat up and then
the solder is attracted to the braid and
it takes it away from the PCB or your
chip okay cool and when we're doing that
we want to be careful not to pull off
any of these pads right because these
pads are connection points uh from the
chip to the board and so there's pads on
the chip that you could accidentally
pull off because you because if the
solder gets cold and then you pull on
the braid you're G to pull off those
those
on the chips or the board but if you
pull them off you're not complet you
might not be screwed because on a 100
like 153 is a pretty standard BGA
there's ones with more there's ones with
like 200 pads and stuff like that but on
like a a 153 BGA chip I think there's
like 12 pads that are actually used all
the other on when you look in the data
sheet it'll say not it'll say NC not
connected or reserved for future use
which is effectively means it's not
connected now but maybe someday they'll
create a new emmc standard and it will
be connected right but most of them are
not connected which means on the PCB
side there are just floating floating
like there are just pieces of copper
copper circles where the chip connects
that are not connected to anything under
the circuit board wow so so so but but
the ones that actually do carry signals
they're going to go down under into the
into the intermediate layers of the PCB
and connect to some electrical component
right to the CPU or something like that
the pads that are not connected anything
are way easier to pull off because of
that there's less resistance right
they're not they are literally not
connected to anything and so
oftentimes and it's funny when you look
at the the pin out for one of those BGA
chips all the pins that are used are on
one side and one time I accidentally
pulled off a ton of pads from the other
side I'm like oh well I'm screwed and
then I go and I look at the at the pin
out of the data sheet and I'm like wait
no I'm fine like I pulled off like 20
pads but I'm but I'm okay you know cuz
all the because all the ones that matter
the like you know the 12 or so that
matter were fine and that makes me feel
so much better dude like to to know that
out of like you know this massive amount
there's like 12 all right I just got to
get there's only if I pull one off
there's only like a 10% chance that that
is actually one that is necessary yeah
and it's even better than that because
again the ones that are easier to pull
off are the ones that you don't care
about because just because of the
physics of how that works so so so when
we clear that off then what we want to
do is we need to apply new solder Balls
to the chip so that we can reattach it
and so I've got these stencil devices
that you lay the chip down in and then
you lay the stencil which is just a
metal shield and then there's this
solder paste there's solder that's in a
paste form that you can spread with a
little squeegee uh almost like you know
and so you fill in all the holes of the
stencil that perfectly uh sit on top of
all
153 uh pads and then uh once you have
enough that solder paste you just hit it
with hot air for about 10 seconds and
they all just they they they turn into
perfect little solder balls I love that
if if you if you did it right if not you
have to take it all off and start over
again but once you have those so balls
there then you just put a light amount
of flux on the PCV not too much because
otherwise it can like swim off to the
side when you beat it up um and but you
blast it with hot air and then it
reattaches perfectly and then you boot
it up and yes you cross your fingers and
you hope that you didn't screw something
up right so so when you're when you're
um going back to chip off when you're
when you're taking the chip off um how
let me ask you this how hot are you
blasting it with air like what do you
normally set it to I think had mine set
to like 750
fit thank you Joel that's what I'm
saying like Joel is like okay so I I
actually made you know I had a really
funny meme in the in the um in the
presentation I did for def Cod where you
know I put up like a particularly like a
younger picture of Joel that's like he
was looking really cool and he like had
his hoodie up and he's like looking like
a hacker and um and I put a bunch of
like little uh bubbles you know around
his face uh thought thought bubbles
whatever and he's like don't don't set
your your freaking hot air gun to like
700 Justin you know you're going to burn
the chip don't pull the the board off
before it's ready Justin you know I
bricked like three devices this time
when I was working with Joel on this um
and uh and so I so appreciated his
guidance with that but man you know when
you're using a a hotter hot you know a
higher setting on that hot air gun yeah
it just goes so much faster you know
with that I mean we we probably sat
there and and um you know went over the
chip for 20 minutes sometimes you know
and and and I think he's correct in that
you know you can't burn burn up chips
and you can cause problems you know with
with higher higher um uh settings and
stuff like that but uh that that's so
gratifying for me to hear I love that I
I am not a scientist let me let let me
be clear I'm an engineer so like what
works is what I do right maybe not like
the technically correct way to do things
like that that's that's how I judge
these methodologies said it to 700 goes
so
fast that's why I do that's great I love
that this is how you go from from
breaking it open to Firmware in an hour
huh you don't spend an hour yeah yeah
yeah I don't got time to wait around for
that shooting it with hot air that's
great man wow that is an advanced
technique man I uh I'm still a little
bit scared about that but definitely
more interested I got to get myself some
of that thread I actually don't have any
of that that um uh you know what is that
the braided wire that you using yeah
yeah yeah braid yeah and uh I saw in
your videos you know essentially you're
just taking that and you're putting the
soldering iron on the back side of it
and just kind of rubbing it over those
those pads I think that that is really
really cool we were trying to do
something simar that that's something
that takes practice because that's where
that's where you're likely to pull the
pads off because you're yeah yeah you're
you're more likely to pull it's kind of
odd using braids for that though because
I feel like braids have more texture to
them and would be more likely to like if
a corner of a pad is sort of like up a
little bit you know getting under it and
like pulling it out I don't know they
they they they are and they do yeah all
right very cool man uh well my favorite
time of the episodes has come let's talk
about some bugs so um we've got missing
secure but on a device and then well I
won't I won't spoil the second part so
take take it away with this uh this bug
that you've prepared for us so yeah uh
yeah so can't talk about the name of the
device or anything like that but it was
a it was a microcontroller based device
which again is is usually the the device
that I'm not as good at targeting but I
think this story actually illustrates my
point that even if you can't completely
understand the firmware or something
like that you can still get something
out of it right like all these tools of
Hardware
hacking they help you solve a problem
they help you find vulnerabilities you
don't need to have all of them at once
so uh so on this microcontroller device
I you know probably the first thing I
did was look for Ur nothing you know
look for Ur J JTAG enabled none of that
going to work but it did have an
external flash chip so I didn't have to
go was going to have to do any glitching
to extract the firmware so uh this was
one of these really easy like eight pin
I think one of the models of the device
had a 16 pin chip but pretty easy to
remove and put back on the board so I
removed it read the firmware out ran
binw walk so this is a microcontroller
firmware it's just a it's just a binary
blob of data and so there's no file
systems to extract but what binw did
identify in it are a few certificates
and I had already been looking at the
Network traffic over that that I saw
from the device I tried some I tried a
man- inth middle attack so I tried using
man inth middle proxy which uh so this
is before I was using [__] I might have
found I might have found a vulnerab I
might have found part two of this
explanation a lot faster if I would have
been using C mum so that's a good
advertisement for it but I was using man
and the M proxy so the way that man in
the middle proxy works by default is it
has its server certificate has a CN the
common name is man in the middle proxy
so or man in the middle proxy CA or
something like that right and so then it
signs it forges certificates so let's
say the traffic that it's trying to
intercept is going to dubdub dub.
example.com then it's going to forge a
certificate with the the server
certificate is going to have the CN of
dubdub dub. example.com and then it's
going to sign it with the
man-in-the-middle proxy CA right and
then it's going to present that to the
the client and see if the client takes
the bait right um and in this case the
device was not taking that that form of
bait so uh so then what I
did is uh yeah so chip off the and read
the firmware and I found that there
there were these certificates they were
in the deer format which is a binary
encoding it's not like the pem file
where you see a bunch of basic 64
encoded stuff it's completely a binary
protocol uh or a file format and then I
was like you know what okay that's the
ca for the traffic that I'm seeing going
out to the Internet so what I'm going to
do okay and and and because I didn't
understand anything about the
microcontroller firmware so I'm like I
need to generate a certificate that has
exactly as many btes as this other
certificate so I need a bite forbite
like duplicate of the certificate but my
key but I need my key to be in there
right so I you know I I I worked with OP
s sell for a while and all the weird
options that I needed to set to get it
exactly the correct number of btes oh my
gosh and so then I took the firmware and
I knew the offset of their D their uh de
certificate so I just you used the DD
command and like some of the arguments
there yeah they have that in yeah yeah
yeah so in DD you can say uh block size
BS equals one and then so then you're
doing things uh one bite at a time
you're dealing with btes uh as the block
size and then then you can say skip so
you can skip a certain number of bites
and then you can say size so size says
how many bites you'll copy from the
source to the destination so I I just
very carefully uh I think in my I think
when I presented this finding I had the
uh Indiana Jones meme of like like
placing in I'm just very carefully
seeing if this S I can I can place the
CT right in place of the other one right
where it was um and so uh I did that and
then I had my and so then I had a new
firmware image and I flashed that back
to the chip soldered it back onto the
board booted it up and now man in the-
Middle proxy can intercept the SSL
traffic uh not all iot devices uh or
manufacturers care about or have in
their threat model secure boot but this
this company did care very much about
that and they called this a high because
I effectively proved that I was able to
get modified firmware to boot
successfully uh by the by the microc
like I said earlier you know grub and
like anything boot related is like not
my [__] like I I do not like that at all
um and so can you talk to me a little
bit about what that process was like you
know I I I'm I'm tracking with you you
know you pull the The Blob out um
obviously this is a uh a microcontroller
system so it's a little bit different
than the way I'm thinking about it
probably but you know you you figure out
you've been walk it you figure out
offsets you overwrite the CT I'm I'm
tracking with you there writing it back
onto that chip is something that I've
never done I mean are you just doing how
do you doing that is that a part of the
the software using so this is going to
be a difference between the way the emmc
readers work they just kind of Mount as
a file system on your computer right but
the ex geeku uh that Universal
programmer that I use you're when you do
a read you do a read of the whole
firmware image on the Chip And you get
an image back one image of the full
length of the chip of everything that's
stored on there so then all I was doing
is I was taking that firmware image
modifying my one little piece with a
certificate and then going back into
that software again it's not as direct
as when you're when you're doing things
on with emmc you you go back into the
software and you you know upload the
file from your computer the modified
image and then you do a right operation
back to the chip so it's all through the
universal programmer in the MMC side if
you've got it just mounted like an SD
card you can just you can just modify it
in in that file system and then just
pull it out and you know slap it back on
the device if in that scenario yes yes
you would be able to do that yeah you
you mount it uh read WR and you yeah
that would totally work W that's that's
crazy man yeah and then I guess if there
was Secure boo that would get in the way
of that right um and and secure boot
definitions differ across you know
manufacturers and stuff like that but in
the context of a microcontroller right
that that certificate I was modifying it
like I wasn't modifying a part of the
file system I was modifying code right
like like that certificate was embedded
in probably in like a c program that
then got compiled for this
microcontroller and loaded into Flash
and basically by by me modifying it and
getting it to boot and operate just
normally right uh well except you know
with trusting my my certificate instead
of the other one
I was able to prove by doing that that
was like a way for me to prove that
there was no validation of the firmware
happening and then I mean they confirmed
that on their side what they need to be
doing is some sort of like check on the
actual binary that is the firmware in
these uh microcontrollers and where
would you even do that check from also
maybe they should have done a check on
the actual certificate itself and said
you know in somewhere El and the code
said hey has this certificate been
tampered with I I don't know how would
they even fix that yeah so so the
typical way that secure boot is
implemented is this is the actual
microcontroller or the CPU will have
some very small internal storage where
you can program in you can burn in a a
public key and then you who are develop
are the firmware developer have that
corresponding private key and you will
sign the
firmware uh with the private key that a
person with the public key IE the CPU or
or the microcontroller can can can
perform that check and it will halt the
CPU if if it if the signature doesn't
validate gotcha wow that's that's pretty
freaking cool dude okay so you you were
able to to modify this uh
microcontroller based firmware binary
blob yep you did it specifically within
this offsets you got aert that would
just create that at that length and that
exact size inserted it in there fire
back up man I can't imagine the rush of
being able to see that traffic you know
oh my gosh that must have been amazing
um and then where do you go from there
yeah so this is a funny part of the
story of how I I stumbled even into a a
larger a more critical vulnerability uh
so okay so I should note that that Mo
that new you know firmware modified CA
certificate that I generated I didn't
put the man in the-middle proxy
certificate in there I created one again
I wanted it to be exact like the
existing one so I created a new
self-signed that was the same common
name the CN of whatever CA they were
using I I don't remember the name of it
but um they were using some kind of
certificate Authority it was probably an
internal company certificate Authority
and so I I just kept that that name
exactly the same so literally the only
difference between my certificate and
theirs was the the key was the public
key portion of this certificate this is
actually kind of like the implementation
of this a certain minum attack in a
that's one of those attacks I I stumbled
into yeah exact and that's why I say
certaint mum would have caught what I
found next and that is that okay so if
the device was 100% doing certificate
validation the correct way then my with
in this new modified State the device
would only trust my
fake CA certificate not the real one
from from the real server right so I had
to keep my man- in- the- middle setup
running in theory for the device to be
operational well I was like doing
something I had some you know problem
with my computer um it was probably the
only time Arch Linux ever had a problem
yeah you know you never have to reboot
that um but I rebooted and I like forgot
to set up my man- in- the- middle setup
again and I turned the device on and
then I had this realization of like oh I
forgot to put my man inth middle uh you
know setup in there the device probably
isn't working now because it doesn't
trust the certificate on the server and
it's modified State and then I like
checked with the mobile app or some way
you know and I'm like oh it's working
like and then I'm like like there's at
this point I'm like there is something
terribly wrong with with the device
firmware and so so yeah so I effect
you're right I effectively performed the
ctmm attack where I created
a a CA only I put it on the device not
not not in the man- in the middle proxy
where uh it had the same exact uh where
I wasn't just faking I wasn't just
faking the server certificate I was
faking the CA and the server certificate
and it turns out that on this device
what it was doing what it was programmed
to do was programmed to check when it
when the client connected to the TLs
server and it got the server back the
only thing it was was checking in that
certificate was that the the ca who
signed that certificate had the CN
equals to whatever string value it
expected what the heck and so so anyone
obviously can craft a self-signed
certificate with that value in there and
perform a man in the middle and this led
to account takeover because there were
you know I mean it was like the devices
like auth all the devices Communications
which included its authentication
credentials were in that TLS you know I
wonder if this type of attack is more
common on microcontroller based devices
because they're not relying on you know
I say these battle tested libraries
there's like a ton of CVS that dropped
with the [__] thing of like
every uh TLS validation software out
there had a a cve but you know they're
not using these more trusted methods of
doing that they're they're often
optimizing for size because those things
the storage on those devices are much
smaller um so I wonder if they're
they're cutting corners on on TLS imple
100% right and so so often times when
you get a certain brand or a certain
type of microcontroller you will be
provided with an SDK that will include
utilities for making web requests like
you know connecting to W to Wi-Fi um and
so yeah they will there will be a A
diversity of functionality whereas when
it's a Linux device if it's if it's you
know connecting to Wi-Fi it's like yeah
it's going to use WPA supplicant it's
going to act the same way every time or
when it's making a web request it's like
oh they're probably using lib curl or
you know some common library right uh
that is Battle tested yeah you see a
bunch more sketchy [__] and iot hacking
stuff which is really fun I think that's
one of the things that's really exciting
about it too um so all right man we've
done it we've made it through the whole
dock thank you so much for doing this
this was a uh really eye-opening talk on
on iot hacking stuff um yeah I'm
definitely reimbold to go after iot
hacking targets once uh when I can get
my hands on a program to do that um so
thank you so much man thanks for having
me on of
course and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
ACC to master classes amas hack along
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there
[Music]